Now that we have our environment fully setup
现在我们的环境已经配置完毕
let's get the player ship moving under our control.
下面让我们的飞船按照我们的控制飞行吧
To do this we need to write some very simply code.
我们需要写一些简单的代码
We will be writing in C#, which is one of the
代码用C#编写,它是Unity支持的
3 scripting languages supported by Unity.
3种脚本语言之一
To stay organised we need somewhere in our
为了结构清晰,我们需要建立一个文件夹
project to store our new scripts.
来保存我们的新脚本
Let's add a new folder to the root level
我们在Assets目录里的根目录
of our Assets folder.
建立一个新文件夹
It's worth noting that this folder could be placed
这个目录在Assets目录下的什么位置
anywhere within our Assets folder to work
其实都可以正常运行
but for clarity it would seem that the root
但是为了清晰明了
level is the best location for such
根目录是放这种重要文件夹
an important folder.
最好的位置
Select Assets to make sure that we
单击选择Assets文件夹
build this folder on the root level
确定我们的新文件夹的确在Assets文件夹的根目录下
otherwise we will have to move it after
否则我们就要把刚建好的新文件夹
we have created it.
移过来
Use the Create menu in the Project view
使用Project视窗的Create菜单
and select Folder.
选择Folder
This will create a new folder in Assets.
这样会在Assets目录下新建一个文件夹
This new folder will automatically make
这个文件夹的
itself ready to edit.
名称会自动变为可编辑模式
Let's change the name to Scripts,
让我们把名字改为Scripts
and hit Enter or Return to accept
敲击Enter或者Return
the change of the name.
来确认变更的文件夹名称
Now let's create and add a new script
现在让我们为我们的玩家飞船
to our player ship.
新建一个脚本
I'm going to quickly reduce the view of these
让我们先把我们玩家对象显示
referenced materials shown at the bottom of
出来的菜单缩短,
the player game object by clicking on
就这样点击他们的标题栏
the header bars.
就可以把他们最小化
This will make it easier to view and access
这样我们可以让视图看起来简单些
the Add Component button without scrolling.
不用滚动条就能看到Add Component按钮
Next let's click on Add Component
我们来点击一下Add Component按钮
and select New Script.
选New Script
This will allow us to create and add a new script
这会产生一个新的脚本
directly on to our player game object.
这个脚本是玩家对象的脚本
Now let's set the name of the script to
我们将这个脚本命名为
PlayerController.
PlayerController
I feel it's best that we follow the convention of
我们最好遵守一下命名规范
capitalisation shown here, with a capital
大写字母
P and a capital C.
P和C
Script names should start with a capital letter
脚本的名称应该首字母大写
and the capitalisation of the name with the
名称中单词的首字母也要大写
capital C makes the name easier to read.
这样读起来容易一些
Once we have chosen a name we can click on
名字决定好了
Create and Add, or we can simply hit Return
就点击Create and Add或者敲击
or Enter to create and add this script.
Return或者Enter键来添加这个脚本
When we create a script in this manner the script
当我们按照这个步骤新建脚本的时候
will be created on the root level of our project.
自动生成的脚本会建立在项目的根目录下
We need to drag and drop it on to the Scripts folder
我们需要把这个新生成的脚本拖拽到Scripts文件夹下
to file it away properly.
这样便于对文件的管理
Now open the scripts folder to view the script.
现在打开脚本文件夹看看脚本
Let's open the script for editing.
我们需要开始编辑脚本
We can do this in a number of ways.
打开编辑脚本的方法有很多种
1 way is to select the script
其中一种方法是点选这个脚本
and in the Inspector choose Open.
在Inspector视窗中选择Open
This will open the script in MonoDevelop.
这样脚本会在MonoDevelop中打开
MonoDevelop is a companion application
MonoDevelop是Unity自带的一个
that is bundled with Unity.
编译程序
This is the default script editor that comes
这个编译器是Unity默认的编辑器
with Unity, but you can use different
但是我们也可以使用
script editors if you choose.
别的脚本编辑器
For more information please see the details on
更多详细信息请参考下方的
using Unity with other editors linked below.
Unity使用其它编辑器的相关链接.
Before we start I'm going to remove the sample code.
在开始之前我们先把自动生成的代码删除
We will be moving our player ship using physics.
我们飞船的移动是遵循物理法则的
So we will need to use the FixedUpdate function.
所以我们要使用FixedUpdate函数
For more information on both Update and
更多关于Update和FixedUpdate
FixedUpdate and how to use them
的详细信息和使用方法
see the information linked below.
请参考下方连接
So now let's write some code.
现在我们开始写代码
Write void FixedUpdate
写void FixedUpdate
FixedUpdate will be called automatically
在每一个固定的物理步骤之前
by Unity just before each fixed physics step.
FixedUpdate都会被Unity自动调用
All the code we put inside the fixedUpdate
我们放入fixedUpdate函数中的代码
function will be executed once per physics step
在每一个物理步骤执行的时候都会被调用
so write
所以写
float moveHorizontal = input.GetAxis ("Horizontal")
and
和
float moveVertical = input.GetAxis ("Vertical")
This code grabs the input from the player.
这段代码抓取玩家的输入
The axis horizontal and vertical are default
水平和竖直轴这些设定都是在
axis that are preset in the input manager.
input manager(输入管理器)中已经预置好的
Next we need to apply that input
下一步是将这个输入应用于
to the player game object.
玩家游戏对象
We are going to move the player game object
我们将按照物理法则移动玩家游戏对象
using physics, and we are going to do this
我们靠控制玩家对象的速度
by affecting the velocity of the game object directly.
来实现对对象的操作
Now this will result in non-realistic
这个会导致有些行为不怎么符合
physics behaviour, by hey, that's alright,
物理定律,记住我们只是
we are making an arcade game.
在做一个街机游戏,不必如此较真
If we want to make a game that works properly
如果我们要做一个完全按照牛顿物理法则执行
with Newtonian physics we would have
的游戏,那么这个代码的写法
approached this code differently.
就是完全不同的了
The rigidbody component which we attached
我们在建立玩家游戏对象的时候
when we set up the player game object
给该对象添加了一个刚体的组建
is how we work with the built in physics engine.
这个组建是与内置的物理引擎协同工作的
The rigidbody includes properties
刚体插件本身包含的属性有
like UseGravity, Mass and  Drag
UseGravity(使用重力),Mass(块)和Drag(拖拉)
that we can pole, affect and manipulate.
我们可以点选,改变和操作
So if we want to change the physics velocity
所以如果我们想改变游戏对象的
of the player game object we do this
物理速度
by addressing the rigidbody component.
我们需要指定这个刚体组件
So let's write rigidbody.velocity
让我敲下代码rigidbody.velocity
Now rigidbody.velocity uses a Vector3 value.
rigidbody.velocity使用Vector3()值
This gives us the direction we are travelling,
Vector3()值给出了运动的方向和
and how fast we are travelling
运动的快慢
as a vector and it's magnitude.
快慢由向量的标量决定
For more information on the Vector3 class
关于Vector3类及向量的运算
and vector maths please see the
的更多详细信息
details linked below.
请参考下方连接
So our rigidbody velocity will be equal
因此我们的刚体的运动速度等于
some vector3 value.
vector3的值
But what?
但是是哪个vector3值呢?
Well, as we know, a vector3 is made out of
恩,我们知道vector3是由3个浮点数组成的
3 float numbers, an X, a Y and a Z value.
X,Y和Z
Well, what do we put in these 3 float values?
这三个数字中存放一些什么值呢?
We want to use our player input.
应该把玩家的输入放到里面.
Let's walk through this one step at a time.
我们来一步步做一下这件事
How much do we want to move on the Y axis?
我们想在Y方向上移动多少呢?
Or up and down?
或者说想上下移动么?
Well, none.
应该不需要
So Y equals 0.0f
因此我们把Y值设定成0.0f
and if we write it this way, 0.0,
如果我们写成0.0
we need the f to indicate to Unity that
我们需要在结尾添加f来告诉Unity
this decimal value is a floating point number.
这个数字是浮点型数据类型
How much do we want to move left to right?
我们需要左右移动么?
Well, that's our moveHorizontal.
是的,这是我们的参数moveHorizontal(水平移动)
Copy moveHorizontal and paste
我们拷贝一下moveHorizontal
it over the X value.
然后用它替换X值
And forward and back?
前后方向呢?
That's the value from moveVertical.
参数moveVertical(垂直移动)
Copy and paste moveVertical
用moveVertical覆盖Z值
So how can we use this vector3
我们该如何使用这个
now that we've made it?
刚建好的vector3值呢
One way is to create a vector3 variable,
一种方是建立一个vector3的变量
let's call it Movement,
我们起名叫Movement
and movement is equal to a
这个参数等于一个新的
new vector3 moveHorizontal, 0.0f, moveVertical.
由moveHorizontal, 0.0f, moveVertical组成的vector3值
In C# we must remember to use
在C#中我们必须要使用
the keyword here.
new这个关键词(英文字幕少了个new)
and our rigidbody velocity is equal to movement.
我们刚体的速度等于movement这个变量
Now let's save this script and return to Unity.
现在我们保存一下脚本然后返回Unity
The first thing we check is the console,
我们要先检查一下console(控制台)
to make sure that there are no errors
查看一下是否有报错
and that everything we wrote has compiled properly.
并且我们刚写的代码页已经正确编译了
If there were an error we would also see
如果代码有错误
this error in the footer, as our most recent error
报错会出现在页脚
or message will always be shown in the footer.
我们的最新报错或者信息总是会出现在页脚
Let's test our code.
让我们测试一下代码
Save the scene and enter Play mode.
我们保存一下场景然后进入运行模式
We can move our ship,
我们可以移动飞船
but it's moving very very slowly.
不过飞船移动的有点慢
This is because inputGetAxis only returns
这是因为inputGetAxis这个函数只会返回
a number between 0 and 1.
一个0,1之间的数
So our ship's movement with this code
所以我们代码里面的移动效果
will never be more than 1 unit per second.
永远也不会超过每秒1个单位
Let's exit Play mode and return to our
让我们退出运行模式
PlayerController script.
打开PlayerController脚本
We need control over our speed.
我们得控制一下飞船的移动速度
So let's create a new public
让我们建立一个新的public的
float variable called Speed.
浮点型参数命名为Speed
This variable will hold a value we can
我们使用这个参数乘以
use to multiply our input with
我们的输入
as our input will only be a value of 0 to 1.
(我们的输入值在0,1之间)
By multiplying our input by Speed
作为我们的速度
we will be able to move our ship from
我们可以将飞船的速度限定
0 up to a maximum of our Speed value.
在0到Speed参数值之间的值
Now, multiply our movement value by Speed.
现在将我们的movement值与Speed值相乘
Let's return to Unity.
回到Unity
We did not assign a value to Speed in our script.
我们在脚本中并没有给Speed参数赋值
Because we made Speed a public variable
因为我们将Speed设置为public variable(公共变量)
we can see it, we can set it and
我们可以看到并设定这个值
we can change it value in Unity.
我们在Unity中也可以修改这个值
Let's look at our player controller component.
我们先看一下player controller这个组件
We can now see an editable property called Speed.
我们看到一个可编辑的属性叫Speed
Let's change it's value to 10.
我们把这个值设定为10
Now we save and play,
保存并运行一下
and now we can move much faster around the game area.
现在我们的移动速度已经快多了
10 times faster as a matter of fact,
10倍的原始速度
but we have a problem,
但是有个新问题
and that problem is our player ship
我们的玩家飞船
can leave the game area.
会从游戏区域离开
We have no idea where the ship has gone,
我们不知道飞船去哪了
and it would be very easy to completely
这样很容易彻底把飞船搞丢了
loose track of where our ship is.
没办法跟踪飞船的位置
We need to constrain the ship
我们需要限制一下飞船
within the game area.
让它只能在游戏区域里面
So leave Play mode and return
让我们停下运行模式
to our PlayerController script.
切回PlayerController脚本的编辑
We are moving our ship by setting
我们移动飞船是靠
the rigidbody's velocity.
设定它的刚体的速度
We can constrain the ship
我们也可以通过飞船的位置
by setting the value of the rigidbody's position.
来约束飞船的不让它飞出游戏区域
Again, this won't give us realistic
再强调一次,这个会造成物理运动不真实的
physics behaviour, but in our
感觉,但是就我们当前这个项目来说
case it's not necessary.
真实物理运动的感觉并不重要
Unity executes our code within a given
Unity执行我们给定的函数的时候
function 1 line at a time from top to bottom.
是按照从顶端到底端一行行执行的
The code we have written moves our player ship.
我们刚写的代码可以让我们的飞船移动
We will write code that will come after
我们会在这部分移动飞船
the code that moves our ship
的代码下面添加新代码
and if we have moved outside of the game
来实现如果我们飞船飞出游戏区域
the code will set the player's position
就把飞船的位置重新置回游戏区域
back to the edge of the game area.
边缘这个功能
Because Unity will read and execute
因为Unity会在更新每帧图像前
all of the code in our relevant function
读取并执行
before updating the frame
函数的所有的相关代码
the ship itself will never leave the game area.
因此飞船永远也离不开游戏区域
So let's write
所以让我们写一下
rigidbody.position
and this is the property we want to set,
这是我们想要设定的属性
and then write
然后敲
new vector3 (X,Y, Z)
and this is the value we want to set it to.
我们需要在这个里面设定值
The code we are going to write next
我们接下来要写的代码
will make 1 very long line.
会是很长的一行代码
So I'm going to break this code over
我将把这行代码切成
several lines vertically.
几行并竖直对应好
This will all be the same instruction to the compiler.
这对于编译器来说跟写在一行上没什么区别
I'm going to follow the same indenting and
我将保持我们之前使用的
bracket conventions that we are already using
代码结构和缩进格式
for organisation and readability.
这样可以使得代码看起来清晰易读
Let's think about how much we want
让我们考虑一下需要把移动
to limit our movement.
限制在什么范围
How much margin do we want up and down?
上下方向需要限制范围么?
None.
不用
Our player game object should never leave
我们的玩家飞船从来都不会离开
the plane of the game.
游戏的这个平面
The Y value, let's set this to 0.
所以Y方向的值设定成0就好了
But what about left/right and forward/back?
但是上下左右方向呢
The ship is moving along the X/Z plane
我们在X轴和Z轴组成的这个平面上运动
and we want to clamp it within the game area.
我们需要把飞船限制在游戏区域中
The ship starts at origin, or (0, 0, 0)
飞船的起始点是原点或者说(0, 0, 0)
so we want to set limits on all 4 directions
我们需要在X/Z平面的
along the X/Z plane.
四个方向上都做限制
Let's return to our script.,
我们切回脚本编辑器
So write Mathf.
敲一下Mathf
What is Mathf?
什么是Mathf?
Well let's look this up in the documentation.
让我们看一下文档
And remember the shortcut to Unity's
Unity搜索文档
scripting reference in the documentation is
有个快捷键
command+' on the mac
mac机器上是command+'
and control+' on windows.
windows机器上是control+'
Mathf is well worth remembering.
Mathf绝对值得你记住
It is a collection of really useful
它是很多简单易用
easy to use math functions.
的数学方法的集合体
These include variables like Epsilon
(数学常量)其中包含Epsilon
Infinity and Pi,
Infinity(无穷),Pi
and functions like Sine, Cosine, Tangent,
函数包括Sine, Cosine, Tangent,
Square Root, Power, PingPong, Repeat,
Square Root(开方), Power(次方), PingPong(参见文档), Repeat(参见文档),
and even Perlin Noise Generation.
甚至还有柏林噪声生成器
What we are looking for is a function called Clamp.
我们要找的函数是Clamp
Clamp will clamp any given value
Clamp会把数据限制在
between a minimum and a maximum value.
最大最小值之间
We will use this to clamp the position of
我们用它来限制玩家飞船的位置
our player's ship in to our game area.
让玩家飞船始终在游戏区域中
Returning to our script let's write
切回我们的脚本，敲下代码
Clamp (rigibody.position.x, xMin, xMax)
and for Z let's write
Z让我们这么写
Mathf.Clamp (rigidbody.position.z, xMin xMax)
Mathf.Clamp (rigidbody.position.z, zMin zMax)(这里英文字幕又写错了)
This will effectively clamp our position
这就会有效的限定我们玩家飞船的位置
between the values we set for our min
让它在我们指定的X轴和Z轴
and our max on the X and Z axis.
的区间运动
Now we need to declare our min and max values.
现在我们需要声明一下min和max变量
At the top of our script write
在脚本开头写下
public float xMin, xMax, ZMin, zMax
public float xMin, xMax, zMin, zMax(英文字幕z要小写)
and using this format we can define
我们用这个格式
all 4 float variables on 1 line of code.
用一行代码完成4个浮点型的参数的声明
Save the script and return to Unity.
保存脚本回到Unity
Let's look at our player controller component
让我们看一下玩家对象的
on the player game object.
player controller组件
We can see these new properties
我们可以看到这些属性了
but to me they seem to take up a large
但是在我看来这些属性占据了
amount of space in the Inspector.
Inspector视图好大一块位置
Moreover, these properties can
更过分的是,这些属性仅能在当前
only be used by this script.
脚本中使用
There is a way that we can both clean up
我们想让这些代码简洁一些
this code and make it reusable.
并且可以复用
That is to put these in to a separate
那就是把这些代码放到一个单独
class of their own.
的类当中
Let's return to our script
我们先退回到脚本编辑器
and let's move these in to their own class.
我们为这些代码建立一个新的类
We start by defining a new class with
先定义一个新的
public class
公共类
and then we will name our class Boundary.
这个类命名为Boundary
We will follow these with brackets to hold our code.
我们用大括号把代码括起来
It's worth noting that this class
需要注意的是
will not inherit from anything
这个类与PlayerController不同
like our PlayerController class does.
它不需要从父类继承
The : MonoBehaviour that comes after the class name
写在类名字后面的: MonoBehaviour
in our PlayerController class indicates that
告诉我们PlayerController这个类是继承了
this class is inheriting from MonoBehaviour.
MonoBehaviour这个类
For more information on classes
更多关于类的继承和
inheritance and monobehaviour
monobehaviour类
please see the information linked below.
的信息请参考下方连接
Next, let's move our variable definitions from
下一步是把变量的定义从
PlayerController to Boundary.
PlayerController类移动到Boundary类
So how do we use this new Boundary class?
Boundary类该如何用呢?
First we need to make an instance of it
首先在PlayerController类中
in our PlayerController.
建立一个Boundary类的实例
So write public Boundary boundary;
代码是Boundary boundary
and note the capitalisation.
注意一下大小写
Boundary with a capital B is our type
Boundary大写了首字母B
as defined by the class name.
定义的是类名称
Boundary with a lowercase b is
boundary小写了首字母b
the name for our reference in the same way
是实例名称对应了那4个变量
that Speed is the name for our float variable.
就像Speed的用法一样
Next we need to update our Clamp code
然后，我们Clamp里面的代码也得更新一下
to reflect the changes that we have just made.
因为我们改了前面的代码
xMin is now part of our Boundary class,
xMin现在是Boundary类里面的一员了
which we access through the reference
我们可以通过引用的实例来
that we made to our instance
使用这个参数
by using Boundary.xMin.
代码是Boundary.xMin
This is true for xMax,
同样的操作xMax
zMin,
and zMax as well.
和zMax
Let's make our code neat and tidy
我们对齐缩进一下
by aligning our indents.
让代码看起来更整洁
Save the script, switch back to Unity
保存一下代码,然后切换回Unity
and let's look at the updated component.
让我们看一下组件的变化
Hmm, now we can't see our new updated
嗯,刚更新的属性
properties at all.
已经连看都看不到了
This is because the new class
这是因为
that we have created is unknown to
我们刚新建的类
and is therefore not serialised.
系统并不知道它的存在因此没有序列化
Serialising is a way of storing
序列化是存储和传送
and transferring information
信息的方法
Serialisation is a complicated issue.
序列化是很复杂的
At this point, just understanding
目前我们只需要知道
that Unity needs to have properties
Unity的Inspector视图中的属性
serialised to view them in the Inspector
是需要先被序列化后才能看到的
So let's switch back to our script.
我们再回到脚本编辑
To serialise our new class we need to use
要序列化我们的类我们需要代码
[system.serializable]
in square brackets on the line before
在类声明前一行使用这句方括号
we declare our class to make sure
这样刚声明的类
that the class is serialised
就是可以被序列化的
and therefore visible in the Inspector.
这样Inspector视图中就可以见到它了
Save the script and return to Unity.
保存脚本后切换回Unity
Now if we look back at our Player Controller
现在我们再看眼Player Controller组件
we can see Boundary.
我们可以看到Boundary属性了
Turn down the gizmo and we can now see our
点左侧的小三角图标
properties in an easy to use
这样属性就会展开
but very tidy container.
这么做整体看起来既小又方便
We can also use this class in
而且这个类也可以在
other places in our game.
游戏的其他地方使用
Now that we have our properties available to us
现在属性已经有了
let's set their values.
我们给他们赋值吧
Make sure that we have the player ship selected.
首先确定玩家飞船已经选定
So what values do we need to set
xMin 和 xMax 该设定
for xMin and xMax?
什么值呢?
Simply drag the ship to the edge of the game area
把飞船拖到游戏区域的边界上看看
and note the values on the X axis.
注意一下X轴的值
These seem to be about -6 and 6.
差不多是-6 到 6
So let's set these values to a good round
我们把这个值设定为
-6 and 6.
-6 到 6
Doing the same thing along the Z axis,
Z轴也这么做
that's about -4 along the bottom
底部是-4
but along the top edge we don't really
对于顶部来说
want to give our player access to the
我们并不想让玩家达到屏幕的
entire upper game area.
最顶端
We will need to give the hazards in our game
我们需要给我们的小行星碎片留出
some room to be able to enter the game area.
一定空间来进入游戏场景
So let's back off a little bit
所以让我们把飞船后退一点
say about 7 or 8.
差不多7或者8的样子
Let's make zMin and zMax -4 and 8.
让我们设定zMin 为-4 然后 zMax 为8
This will give us a square playable area
这下飞船的移动空间是一个
in our game and reserve
方形空间
a little room for hazards at the top.
顶端给小行星预留了位置
Now let's reset the player's transform
我们把玩家飞船的变形组件重置一下
and let's test.
然后测试一下效果
Enter Play mode,
运行游戏
and we can see that we are now clamped
现在我们的运动区域限定在
inside the game area.
游戏区域内了
Exit Play mode.
退出运行模式
Now we are essentially done with our
现在我们玩家对象算是处理完毕了
player game object, but I think it's worth
不过让我们在进行下一步之前
adding 1 bit of fun to it before we move on.
再加点好玩的东西
Let's add some bank, or tilt to the
让我们把飞船沿X轴飞行时
player ship when we move from side
增加以一下飞船
to side along the X axis.
的倾斜
Switch to our script and let's create
先切回脚本编辑模式
a new variable to hold our tilt value.
建一个新的参数用来保存倾斜的数据
Next, after the code we have written
然后在我们写的代码的后面
but still in FixedUpdate write
仍然在FixedUpdate里面
rigidbody.rotation = Quaternion.Euler.
写代码rigidbody.rotation = Quaternion.Euler
And yes, it is pronounced oiler,
是的这个东西发音是oiler
which is also an X, Y and Z value.
这个也包含了X, Y 和 Z的值
For more information on Quaternions and
更多关于Quaternions和Quaternion.Euler
Quaternion.Euler see the links below.
的详细信息请参考下方连接
We only want to tilt, or bank,
我们只需要沿Z方向
along the Z axis
倾斜飞行
so X and Y are set to 0.
所以X和Y值设定成0
And Z?
Z方向怎么设定呢?
We want the tilt along the Z axis to
Z方向倾斜的情况应该取决于
be related to how fast we are moving
我们左右移动的速度
left to right, so our rotation on the Z axis
所以Z应该等于
is equal to our rigidbody.velocity X
rigidbody.velocity中的X
which is our velocity from left to right
这个值是我们左右移动的速度
multiplied by our tilt factor.
然后乘我们的tilt参数
So we can control the maximum amount of bank.
这样我们可以控制最大的倾斜角度
The only correction we need to make this code is
这里唯一需要我们改的地方时
to multiply by negative tilt.
乘负的tilt
Otherwise our ship will tilt in the opposite
否则我们fe1飞船倾斜的方向
direction to what we want.
会与我们预计的方向相反
Save the script and return to Unity
保存脚本回到Unity
and let's set the tilt value.
让我们设定以下tilt的值
Let's try 3.
先试一下3
If we feel it needs to tilt more
如果我们需要更大角度的倾斜
we can simply adjust the tilt property
简单增大以下下这个
with a higher value.
参数就好了
Let's try 4.
试下4
4 feels good.
4更好点
Incidentally, when the ship is banked over
顺便提一句,当船倾斜得时候
it picks up a good combination
补光和边远光在右侧的组合
of our fill and rim lights on the left side.
看起来很不错
That completes the code for moving our player ship.
现在我们玩家飞船的代码写完了
In the next assignment we will continue with
下一个目标是编辑出
our game play by creating shots
让我们的玩家飞船可以
for our player to shoot.
发射子弹